usnews.com 2019-06-30

# Privacy Policy

Last updated September 6, 2018.

Welcome to usnews.com, which is published by U.S. News & World Report, L.P. ("U.S. News"). This Privacy Policy applies to [www.usnews.com](https://www.usnews.com/), our paid content, and any other of our websites, digital services or mobile or other applications on which a link to this Privacy Policy appears (collectively, the "U.S. News Services"), all of which U.S. News Services are provided by U.S. News at any time and from time to time in its sole discretion. U.S. News may change, suspend or discontinue any or all of the U.S. News Services at any time. U.S. News does not control and is not responsible for, and this Privacy Policy does not apply to, any third-party site to which the U.S. News Services link or that links to any U.S. News Services.

You agree that your use of the U.S. News Services is subject to this Privacy Policy. **If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy in its entirety, please do not use any U.S. News Services.** This Privacy Policy may be modified at any time and from time to time; the date of the most recent changes or revisions will appear on this page. Continued access to the U.S. News Services by you will constitute your acceptance of any changes or revisions to this Privacy Policy.

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area ("EEA") or Switzerland, please see the "Users in the EEA and Switzerland" section of this Privacy Policy.

Information Collected by U.S. News

U.S. News and third parties may collect personally identifiable information from you such as your name, telephone number, postal address, e-mail address, and credit card information so that we (on our own behalf or on behalf of third parties) or other third parties can provide you with the products and services you request or have agreed to receive. For example, we may ask you for your name, e-mail address, and certain other information in connection with certain features of the U.S. News Services. U.S. News may also collect your credit card information when you make a purchase, so that we can process your payment for the product or service you are requesting. During the ordering process, such credit card information is transmitted either to U.S. News or to the particular supplier or service provider who provides the service you are purchasing. In both cases, credit card information is then transmitted to third-party credit card processors and card issuers that use your information to process your order.

U.S. News may also collect information that does not identify you by name when you visit the U.S. News Services, such as your internet protocol ("IP") address, geo-location, domain name, browser configuration, device type, unique device identifier, the type of operating system you are using, information about your Internet service provider, the time of your visit, whether you are a returning visitor, and any referring website.

U.S. News may also collect information about you from publicly and commercially available sources, as permitted by law, which we may combine with other information we receive from or about you.

How We Use Information Collected from Users

We or our service providers may use the information you supply to fulfill your requests for products and services, to respond to your inquiries, and to offer other products and services from either us or third parties which may be of interest to you. If you choose to submit comments or other content for publication, we may publish your name, screen name or such other information that you supply.

If you have indicated interest in receiving information directly from a third party, we may provide such third party with information that may include but not be limited to your name, telephone number, postal address and email address. If you decide that you do not wish to receive further communications from such third party, you will need to so notify such third party.

Certain outside companies offer promotions on the U.S. News Services through which such outside companies directly collect personal information from you. In those instances, you are providing your personal information directly to the outside company and not to U.S. News, although such outside companies may share your personal information with U.S. News. U.S. News is not responsible for the privacy practices of such outside companies.

We may use information we collect from and about you to facilitate the delivery of targeted advertising to you on the U.S. News Services and on third party websites on behalf of U.S. News or third party advertisers. See "Use of Cookies" below.

We sometimes use information that we or our service providers collect through our use of cookies and other tracking technologies to manage and optimize the U.S. News Services, including to improve the design, delivery and content of the U.S. News Services and to enable us to personalize your user experience. We may also use the information we collect in the aggregate to analyze how visitors use the U.S. News Services or for other purposes, and we may share such aggregated data with third parties. See "Use of Cookies" below.

In addition, U.S. News may disclose information we maintain (A) if in good faith we believe that such disclosure is necessary to (1) comply with the law or legal process; (2) protect and defend our rights and property; (3) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of the U.S. News Services; or (4) protect the personal safety, property, or rights of our users or the public, or (B) in connection with a corporate transaction, such as a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale.

Data Security

We use commercially reasonable physical, technical and administrative controls to protect the information we collect online. Please note that since no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage, is completely secure, we are unable to guarantee security of your information.

Links to Third-Party Sites

The U.S. News Services may link to third-party websites and services that are outside of our control. U.S. News is not responsible for the privacy or security of any information collected by such third-party websites or services. You should review the privacy policies applicable to any such third-party websites or services that you use.

How to Unsubscribe from Email

If you decide that you do not wish to receive email communications from U.S. News and others, you may opt-out of receiving further e-mails and other communications by clicking "Unsubscribe" or "Manage my email preferences" in any email.

Use of Cookies

U.S. News and some advertisers, service providers and other third parties that help manage and optimize the U.S. News Services may place cookies on your computer or mobile device in connection with your use of the U.S. News Services.

"Cookies" are pieces of information that are placed in a storage place on your computer or mobile device when you visit the U.S. News Services. Cookies recognize your web browser; they do not contain information that is, in itself, personally identifying unless you have specifically provided such information. While you can disable cookies (follow your web browser's instructions to do so), it may interfere with the proper functioning of the U.S. News Services. Because an industry-standard Do-Not-Track protocol has not yet been established, our information collection practices on the U.S. News Services will continue to operate as described in this Privacy Policy regardless of any "Do Not Track" signals that may be sent by certain browsers. However, you may refuse to accept cookies in order to prevent tracking activities. Please note that your web browser may not permit you to block the use of non-cookie tracking technologies, and those browser settings that block cookies may have no effect on such techniques.

Cookies and other tracking technologies are placed on your computer or mobile device to improve the design, delivery and content of the U.S. News Services and to enable us to personalize your user experience. Cookies help deliver and measure the effectiveness of advertisements, calculate unique site visitors, track usage throughout our site, and make the login process more convenient for the U.S. News Services that use logins.

Advertisers and service providers may use cookies and other tracking technologies to recognize your computer or device and/or to collect and record information about your visits to the U.S. News Services and other websites, so that they can facilitate feature functionality, measure the effectiveness of ads, to track page usage and paths followed during visits, and to provide advertisements about goods and services they think will be of interest to you based on your usage. These companies may provide this data to us. We do not have access to or control over these advertisers' or service providers' use of cookies or other tracking technologies or how they may be used. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click [here](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/#completed) or [here](https://www.aboutads.info/).

We also contract with certain third parties to help manage and optimize the U.S. News Services who may also use cookies or other tracking technologies to collect information about your use of the U.S. News Services. Some of the things this information is used for include delivering advertisements, measuring the effectiveness of advertisements, and learning how visitors use the U.S. News Services. For more information about such third parties, click here.

Information for Users in Europe and Elsewhere Outside of the United States

If you use the U.S. News Services outside of the United States, you understand that U.S. News may collect, process, and store your personal information in the United States and other countries. The laws in the U.S. regarding personal information may be different from the laws of your state or country. Any transfers of personal information will comply with safeguards as required by relevant law. If applicable, you may have a right to claim compensation for damages caused by a breach of relevant data protection laws.

Users in the European Economic Area ("EEA") and Switzerland

If you are a resident of the EEA or Switzerland, the following information applies with respect to personal data collected through your use of the U.S. News Services.

Purposes of processing and legal basis for processing

As explained above, U.S. News processes personal data in various ways depending upon your use of the U.S. News Services. We process personal data on the following legal bases: (1) with your consent; (2) as necessary to perform our agreement to provide the U.S. News Services; and (3) as necessary for our legitimate interests in providing the U.S. News Services where those interests do not override your fundamental rights and freedom related to data privacy.

Right to lodge a complaint

Users that reside in the EEA or Switzerland have the right to lodge a complaint about our data collection and processing actions with the supervisory authority concerned. Contact details for data protection authorities are available [here](http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080).

Withdrawing Consent

If you wish to withdraw your consent to the use of technologies such as cookies to deliver relevant advertising on the U.S. News Services and across the internet, personalize content and perform site analytics, you should disable cookies on your browser by following your web browser's instructions. Once you do so, you will not be able to access the U.S. News Services unless you subsequently provide your consent for the use of such technologies.

Third Party Tracking Technologies

More information about third party tracking technologies on the U.S. News Services, including the ability to opt out, is available here.

Transfers

Personal information we collect may be transferred to, and stored and processed in, the United States or any other country in which we or our affiliates or subcontractors maintain facilities. U.S. News will ensure that transfers of personal information to a non-EEA country or an international organization are subject to appropriate safeguards.

Your Rights

You are entitled to the rights under Chapter III of the EU General Data Protection Regulation or Section 2 of the Swiss Federal Act on Data Protection with respect to the processing of your personal data, which include the right to access and rectify your personal data and to request erasure of your personal data. To exercise these rights, contact [webmaster@usnews.com](mailto:webmaster@usnews.com).

Children Under Age 13 (16 in EEA and Switzerland)

No one under the age of 13 should provide any personally identifiable information to U.S. News. U.S. News does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 without verified parental consent. In the event that we learn that we have collected such information from a child under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete this information from our database as quickly as possible. If you believe the U.S. News Services has collected any personally identifiable information about anyone under 13, please contact us at [webmaster@usnews.com](mailto:webmaster@usnews.com). For residents of the EEA and Switzerland, the provisions of this paragraph apply to children under the age of 16.

California Residents

Users of the U.S. News Services who are California residents may request certain information pursuant to California Civil Code Section 1798.83 regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to [webmaster@usnews.com](mailto:webmaster@usnews.com) with "Request for California Privacy Information" in the subject line and in the message.

Cookies on the U.S. News Services

U.S. News relies on third parties to provide many features of the U.S. News Services. Some of them use data about your use of the U.S. News Services and other sites. Below is a list of third parties with links to more information their use of your data.

Site Operations

These cookies enable features that are necessary for providing the U.S. News Services to you, such as loading required scripts, serving video content, or providing email signup services.

Partner

| 

Learn more about use of data:  
  
---|---  
|   
Brightcove Player| [here](https://www.brightcove.com/en/legal/services-privacy-policy)  
Ensighten| [here](https://www.ensighten.com/privacy-policy/)  
Google Tag Manager| [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites)  
Kaltura| [here](https://corp.kaltura.com/privacy-policy#Privacy%20Notice%20for%20the%20Kaltura%20Platform)  
Sailthru - These cookies will not load for users in the EEA and Switzerland.| [here](https://www.sailthru.com/legal/#privacy-statement)  
Tealium| [here](https://tealium.com/products/tealium-iq-tag-management-system/)  
  
Site Analytics

These cookies allow us to understand how the U.S. News Services are being used, track site performance and make improvements.

Partner

| 

Learn more about use of data:  
  
---|---  
|   
Catchpoint| [here](http://www.catchpoint.com/trust/#tab-privacy)  
ComScore - These cookies will not load for users in the EEA and Switzerland.| [here](https://www.comscore.com/About-comScore/Privacy-Policy)  
Crazy Egg| [here](https://www.crazyegg.com/privacy)  
GA Audiences| [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites)  
Google Analytics| [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites)  
Index Exchange - These cookies will not load for users in the EEA and Switzerland.| [here](http://www.indexexchange.com/privacy/)  
New Relic| [here](https://newrelic.com/termsandconditions/privacy)  
Omniture (Adobe Analytics)| [here](https://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html#customeruse)  
Parsely| [here](https://www.parse.ly/privacy-policy/)  
PowerReviews| [here](https://www.powerreviews.com/privacy-policy/)  
Scorecard Research Beacon - These cookies will not load for users in the EEA and Switzerland.| [here](https://www.scorecardresearch.com/privacy.aspx?newlanguage=1)  
Snowplow - These cookies will not load for users in the EEA and Switzerland.| [here](https://snowplowanalytics.com/)  
SOASTA mPulse| [here](https://www.soasta.com/performance-monitoring/)  
TrackJS| [here](https://trackjs.com/privacy/)  
Visual Website OptimizerVisual Website Optimizer| [here](https://vwo.com/privacy-policy/)  
  
Advertising

These cookies are to make advertising messages more relevant to you. They perform functions like preventing the same ad from repeatedly appearing, ensuring that ads are properly displayed for advertisers, and in some cases selecting advertisements that are based on your interests.

Partner

| 

Learn more about use of data:  
  
---|---  
|   
Amazon Associates| [here](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496)  
BlueKai| [here](https://www.oracle.com/legal/privacy/marketing-cloud-data-cloud-privacy-policy.html)  
Datalogix| [here](https://www.oracle.com/legal/privacy/marketing-cloud-data-cloud-privacy-policy.html)  
DoubleClick| [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites)  
Facebook Custom Audience| [here](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/)  
Google AdWords Conversion| [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites%3CPaste%3E)  
Google IMA| [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites)  
Google Publisher Tags| [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites)  
Hubspot| [here](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy)  
Krux Digital - These cookies will not load for users in the EEA and Switzerland.| [here](https://www.salesforce.com/products/marketing-cloud/data-management/)  
Lotame| [here](https://www.lotame.com/about-lotame/privacy/lotames-products-services-privacy-policy/)  
Moat| [here](https://moat.com/privacy)  
Nativo - These cookies will not load for users in the EEA and Switzerland.| [here](https://www.nativo.com/interest-based-ads/)  
Open Adstream - These cookies will not load for users in the EEA and Switzerland.| [here](https://www.appnexus.com/en/company/platform-privacy-policy)  
OpenX - These cookies will not load for users in the EEA and Switzerland.| [here](https://www.openx.com/legal/privacy-policy/)  
Outbrain| [here](https://www.outbrain.com/)  
Rubicon - These cookies will not load for users in the EEA and Switzerland.| [here](https://rubiconproject.com/privacy/)  
Tapad| [here](https://www.tapad.com/privacy-policy)  
Teads - These cookies will not load for users in the EEA and Switzerland.| [here](https://teads.tv/privacy-policy/)  
TradeDesk - These cookies will not load for users in the EEA and Switzerland.| [here](https://www.thetradedesk.com/general/privacy-policy)  
Yieldbot - These cookies will not load for users in the EEA and Switzerland.| [here](https://www.yieldbot.com/platform-privacy-policy/)  
  
Social Media

These cookies enable the sharing of content from the U.S. News Services through social networking and other sites.

Partner

| 

Learn more about use of data:  
  
---|---  
|   
Facebook Connect - These cookies will not load for users in the EEA and Switzerland.| [here](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/)  
AddThis| [here](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy)  
  
How to Contact Us

If you have questions about our Privacy Policy, you may contact us at:

Attention: Peter Dwoskin, Esq.   
U.S. News & World Report L.P.   
120 Fifth Avenue, 7th Floor   
New York, NY 10011   
(t) 212.210.6390
